<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>openwrt on Alex King's blog</title><link>https://blog.hljin.net/en-us/tags/openwrt/</link><description>Recent content in openwrt on Alex King's blog</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://blog.hljin.net/en-us/tags/openwrt/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Deploying Headscale to Build a Private Tailscale Network</title><link>https://blog.hljin.net/en-us/2025/12/deploy-headscale/</link><pubDate>Sun, 07 Dec 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hljin.net/en-us/2025/12/deploy-headscale/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert warning ">
&lt;p>This article is translated from Chinese to English by ChatGPT. There might be errors.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>My private home network originally used Zerotier, but I found the connection to be unstable. Even when both of my nodes had public IPs, they sometimes failed to connect. Later I switched to WireGuard, which turned out to be very stable. Recently, however, I bought several new VPS instances and a friend’s home network also joined mine. The number of nodes increased, security rules became more complex, and maintaining WireGuard started to feel overwhelming. So I finally decided to deploy Headscale and migrate to a Tailscale-based network.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>OpenWrt Hardware Flow Offload Causing MAC Address Caching</title><link>https://blog.hljin.net/en-us/2025/11/flowtable-mac-issue/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://blog.hljin.net/en-us/2025/11/flowtable-mac-issue/</guid><description>&lt;div class="alert warning ">
&lt;p>This article is translated from Chinese to English by ChatGPT. There might be errors.&lt;/p>
&lt;/div>
&lt;p>Ran into yet another pitfall. This time it happened when I tried to migrate my original Proxmox VM ImmortalWrt (a build of OpenWrt) into Docker while keeping the IP address unchanged. This ImmortalWrt instance is running my WireGuard service. The migration itself went smoothly. After starting the Docker container, ping worked fine, and my phone could connect to WireGuard. Only one always-on 24/7 node stubbornly refused to connect: no handshake, WireGuard showed 0 KB received, not a single packet came in.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>